# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hello, everyone. This is Wang Gang.
# 本期视频我给大家分享
In today's video I want to share with you
# 香辣豆豉的做法
how to make Spicy Douchi Sauce
# 首先我们准备豆豉400克
First we get Douchi 400g
# 分出200克将其捏散备用
Take out 200g and crush them
# 这一步的目的是让豆豉碎整各占一半
This step is to make half of the Douchi complete and half mashed
# 捏碎之后将所有豆豉搅拌均匀备用
Then mix the two halves well
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Next we prepare the supplementary ingredients
# 准备生姜80克切成姜末备用
Mince 80g ginger
# 准备大蒜50克切成蒜末备用
Mince 50g garlic
# 准备大葱1小把斜刀切成小段备用
Slant-cut a small handful of spring onions
# 准备蒜苗1小把切成小段备用
Chop a small handful of garlic sprouts
# 下一步开始准备香料
Next we prepare the spices
# 碗中加入八角几颗
Add several star anise into a bowl
# 加入香叶几片
with some bay leaves
# 加入1小把小茴香（约25克）
a small handful of fennel seed (about 25g)
# 加入适量的青花椒（约15克）
and some Sichuan green peppercorn (about 15g)
# 不能吃麻味的同学可以不加
You can leave out the peppercorn if you can't endure the numbing flavor
# 碗中加入适量的白酒搅拌均匀浸泡备用
Add some Baijiu and stir well. Let it soak for a while.
# 这一步的目的是让香料出味
This step is to bring out the flavor of the spices.
# 准备适量的灯笼椒放入碗中备用（主要作用增香）
Have some red bell peppers ready in a bowl (for the flavor)
# 加入适量的子弹头备用（主要作用增色）
Add some "Zidantou" chili pepper (for the color)
# 最后加入适量的干小米辣备用（主要作用增辣）
Finally add some dried "Xiaomila" chili pepper (for the spiciness)
# 同学们所有的干辣椒可以按照自己的口味来添加
You can customize your own dried cili peppers combo
# 下一步开始准备调味料
Next we prepare the seasoning ingredients
# 碗中加入蚝油100克
Add 100g oyster sauce to a bowl
# 加入适量的鸡精（约10克）
Add some chicken bouillon (about 10g)
# 加入少许白糖提鲜
Add some white sugar for umami flavor
# 下一步开始处理辣椒
Next we process the chili peppers
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First we heat up the wok
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的底油
After heated, add some base oil
# 油温4成热之后将准备好的干辣椒下锅炒香炒至棕色
When oil temperature is about 120°C, add the dried peppers. Fry until you smell the aroma and the peppers turn brown
# 辣椒炒香之后倒出备用
Set them aside once done
# 下一步锅中加入适量的清水
Next we add some water into the wok
# 然后放入蒸笼将豆豉下锅蒸20分钟
Then put Douchi on a steamer and steam for 20 minutes
# 这一步的目的是激发豆豉最原始的香味
This step is to enhance the original flavor of Douchi
# 最后趁这个时间将炒香的辣椒放入石臼中捣碎备用
Finally we use this time to grind the chili peppers in a mortar
# 嫌麻烦的同学也可以用料理机打碎
You can also use a blender to save some effort
# 20分钟之后取出蒸好的豆豉
20 minutes later, we take Douchi out
# 下一步开始炒制
Next we make the sauce
# 锅烧热之后加入纯菜籽油1200克
Add 1200g mustard oil after heating up the wok
# 油温烧至5成热之后将切好的大葱和蒜苗下锅
Put in spring onions and garlic sprouts once oil temperature reaches 150°C
# 再加入准备好的香料带着白酒一起下锅
Then add the spices and Baijiu mixture
# 然后转中小火把辅料和香料炸香（香料：八角，小茴香，香叶）
Turn to middle to low heat and fry the spices until you can smell the aroma (spices: star anise, fennel seed, bay leaves)
# 辅料香料炒至干香之后捞出丢弃不用
Pick everything out once dry and used
# 然后我们再次把油温升至6成热
Then we bring oil temperature to around 180°C
# 油温6成热之后加入剁碎的姜蒜末下锅
Add minced garlic and minced ginger
# 同学们这一步把姜蒜末炸香即可
We only need to fry slightly and bring the flavor out in this step
# 料头炸香之后加入蒸好的豆豉下锅
Add steamed Douchi once the smell comes out
# 豆豉下锅之后转小火炒10分钟
Turn to low heat and cook for 10 minutes
# 这一步的目的是把豆豉的水份炒至略干
We want to dry our Douchi in this step
# 10分钟之后加入捣碎的干辣椒面
10 minutes later add ground chili pepper powder
# 然后继续开小火炒15分钟
Then cook at low heat for 15 minutes
# 这一步必须小火慢炒防止辣椒面炒糊
You must be using low heat or you may burn the chili powder
# 15分钟之后关火
15 minutes later turn off the heat
# 再加入配好的蚝油和鸡精搅拌均匀
Add prepared oyster sauce and chicken bouillon and mix well
# 拌匀之后倒出冷却即可食用
Then pour it out, let it cool and that's it
# 一份自制香辣豆豉酱就制作完成
A self-made Spicy Douchi Sauce is finished
# 下面开始技术总结
# 第一，干辣椒最好选用灯笼椒子弹头和小米辣，比例根据个人口味微调
# 第二，豆豉下锅之前必须事先蒸20分钟，这样才能发挥出最大潜力
# 第三，成品之后最好静止12小时再食用才更加入味
# 第四，此酱可以作为万能佐料（下饭，下面条，拌菜，开胃辣椒酱）
# 豆豉香辣将的技术总结完成
Now the technical tips:
First, it's better to use red bell peppers and "Xiaomila" chili peppers. The ratio can be slightly adjusted based on your taste.
Second, Douchi must be steamed for 20 minutes beforehand to get the best result.
Third, let it rest for 12 hours after cooking for better flavored sauce.
Fourth, this sauce is "multi-purposed" (it goes well with rice and noodle, and can be used as dressing for dish or consumed as a regular spicy sauce).
That's all the technical tips for Spicy Douchi Sauce.